Hi there. I have a niece,
Mabel, who's almost three years old.
I used to love feeding her and carrying her around the park.
Around the time she was two years old,
whenever I tried to spoon-feed her,
she would grab the spoon in one hand and say, "Mabel self."
Then she hold a spoon and try to feed herself.
Same thing when I try to pick her up and take her to the park.
She would start kicking her feet and saying, "Mabel walk."
Then once I put her on the ground,
she would start walking herself.
I think it's wonderful that she likes feeling independent.
I think that when we're students and learning something new,
it's normal to feel stuck and it's tempting to want
someone to show us the way that will guarantee a solution.
But when we choose more independence and embrace a bit of struggle,
I think that even if we struggle and make mistakes,
we eventually find the answer.
The process helps us to feel more
confident in ourselves and leads to more meaningful learning.
Goodbye for now and good luck.